<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="15" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:12:12.510" Score="36" ViewCount="2186" Body="&lt;p&gt;How should I elicit prior distributions from experts when fitting a Bayesian model?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastActivityDate="2010-09-15T21:08:26.077" Title="Eliciting priors from experts" Tags="&lt;bayesian&gt;&lt;prior&gt;&lt;elicitation&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="23" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="59" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:12:57.157" Score="29" ViewCount="20123" Body="&lt;p&gt;In many different statistical methods there is an &quot;assumption of normality&quot;.  What is &quot;normality&quot; and how do I know if there is normality?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="88" LastEditDate="2010-08-07T17:56:44.800" LastActivityDate="2016-06-27T06:44:40.147" Title="What is normality?" Tags="&lt;distributions&gt;&lt;normality&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="10" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="5" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:13:28.577" Score="66" ViewCount="5550" Body="&lt;p&gt;What are some valuable Statistical Analysis open source projects available right now?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edit: as pointed out by Sharpie, valuable could mean helping you get things done faster or more cheaply.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="18" LastEditorUserId="183" LastEditDate="2011-02-12T05:50:03.667" LastActivityDate="2013-05-27T14:48:36.927" Title="What are some valuable Statistical Analysis open source projects?" Tags="&lt;software&gt;&lt;open-source&gt;" AnswerCount="19" CommentCount="4" FavoriteCount="39" CommunityOwnedDate="2010-07-19T19:13:28.577" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="135" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:13:31.617" Score="17" ViewCount="21949" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have two groups of data.  Each with a different distribution of multiple variables.  I'm trying to determine if these two groups' distributions are different in a statistically significant way.  I have the data in both raw form and binned up in easier to deal with discrete categories with frequency counts in each.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What tests/procedures/methods should I use to determine whether or not these two groups are significantly different and how do I do that in SAS or R (or Orange)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastActivityDate="2010-09-08T03:00:19.690" Title="Assessing the significance of differences in distributions" Tags="&lt;distributions&gt;&lt;statistical-significance&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="5" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:14:43.050" Score="85" Body="&lt;p&gt;The R-project&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.r-project.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;R is valuable and significant because it was the first widely-accepted Open-Source alternative to big-box packages.  It's mature, well supported, and a standard within many scientific communities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inside-r.org/why-use-r&quot;&gt;Some reasons why it is useful and valuable&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are some nice tutorials &lt;a href=&quot;http://gettinggeneticsdone.blogspot.com/search/label/ggplot2&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastEditorUserId="23" LastEditDate="2010-07-19T19:21:15.063" LastActivityDate="2010-07-19T19:21:15.063" CommentCount="3" CommunityOwnedDate="2010-07-19T19:14:43.050" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:14:44.080" Score="280" ViewCount="89705" Body="&lt;p&gt;Last year, I read a blog post from &lt;a href=&quot;http://anyall.org/&quot;&gt;Brendan O'Connor&lt;/a&gt; entitled &lt;a href=&quot;http://anyall.org/blog/2008/12/statistics-vs-machine-learning-fight/&quot;&gt;&quot;Statistics vs. Machine Learning, fight!&quot;&lt;/a&gt; that discussed some of the differences between the two fields.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewgelman.com/2008/12/machine_learnin/&quot;&gt;Andrew Gelman responded favorably to this&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simon Blomberg: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;From R's fortunes&#xA;  package: To paraphrase provocatively,&#xA;  'machine learning is statistics minus&#xA;  any checking of models and&#xA;  assumptions'.&#xA;  -- Brian D. Ripley (about the difference between machine learning&#xA;  and statistics) useR! 2004, Vienna&#xA;  (May 2004) :-) Season's Greetings!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andrew Gelman:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;In that case, maybe we should get rid&#xA;  of checking of models and assumptions&#xA;  more often. Then maybe we'd be able to&#xA;  solve some of the problems that the&#xA;  machine learning people can solve but&#xA;  we can't!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was also the &lt;a href=&quot;http://projecteuclid.org/euclid.ss/1009213726&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Statistical Modeling: The Two Cultures&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; paper&lt;/a&gt; by Leo Breiman in 2001 which argued that statisticians rely too heavily on data modeling, and that machine learning techniques are making progress by instead relying on the &lt;em&gt;predictive accuracy&lt;/em&gt; of models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Has the statistics field changed over the last decade in response to these critiques?  Do the &lt;em&gt;two cultures&lt;/em&gt; still exist or has statistics grown to embrace machine learning techniques such as neural networks and support vector machines?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="5" LastEditorUserId="22047" LastEditDate="2013-06-07T06:38:10.327" LastActivityDate="2016-08-16T18:12:10.847" Title="The Two Cultures: statistics vs. machine learning?" Tags="&lt;machine-learning&gt;" AnswerCount="19" CommentCount="7" FavoriteCount="275" CommunityOwnedDate="2010-08-09T13:05:50.603" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="18" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:15:59.303" Score="94" ViewCount="32557" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been working on a new method for analyzing and parsing datasets to identify and isolate subgroups of a population without foreknowledge of any subgroup's characteristics.  While the method works well enough with artificial data samples (i.e. datasets created specifically for the purpose of identifying and segregating subsets of the population), I'd like to try testing it with live data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I'm looking for is a freely available (i.e. non-confidential, non-proprietary) data source.  Preferably one containing bimodal or multimodal distributions or being obviously comprised of multiple subsets that cannot be easily pulled apart via traditional means.  Where would I go to find such information?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastEditorUserId="253" LastEditDate="2013-09-26T21:50:36.963" LastActivityDate="2016-03-29T09:06:44.293" Title="Locating freely available data samples" Tags="&lt;dataset&gt;&lt;sample&gt;&lt;population&gt;&lt;teaching&gt;" AnswerCount="26" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="98" CommunityOwnedDate="2010-07-20T20:50:48.483" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:16:21.737" Score="0" ViewCount="332" Body="&lt;p&gt;Sorry, but the emptyness was a bit overwhelming. And this has been stuck in my head since it got asked at Area51!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="37" LastEditorUserId="449" LastEditDate="2010-10-18T07:57:31.170" LastActivityDate="2010-10-18T07:57:31.170" Title="So how many staticians *does* it take to screw in a lightbulb?" Tags="&lt;humor&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="2" ClosedDate="2010-07-19T20:19:46.577" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:16:27.553" Score="13" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://incanter.org/&quot;&gt;Incanter&lt;/a&gt; is a Clojure-based, R-like platform (environment + libraries) for statistical computing and graphics. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="50" LastActivityDate="2010-07-19T19:16:27.553" CommentCount="3" CommunityOwnedDate="2010-07-19T19:16:27.553" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="1887" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:17:47.537" Score="36" ViewCount="40127" Body="&lt;p&gt;Many studies in the social sciences use Likert scales.  When is it appropriate to use Likert data as ordinal and when is it appropriate to use it as interval data?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="919" LastEditDate="2011-03-30T15:31:46.003" LastActivityDate="2012-10-23T17:33:41.907" Title="Under what conditions should Likert scales be used as ordinal or interval data?" Tags="&lt;scales&gt;&lt;measurement&gt;&lt;ordinal&gt;&lt;interval&gt;&lt;likert&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="4" FavoriteCount="19" />
  <row Id="11" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="1201" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:18:30.810" Score="3" ViewCount="264" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is there a good, modern treatment covering the various methods of multivariate interpolation, including which methodologies are typically best for particular types of problems? I'm interested in a solid statistical treatment including error estimates under various model assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An example:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inverse_distance_weighting&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Shepard's method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Say we're sampling from a multivariate normal distribution with unknown parameters. What can we say about the standard error of the interpolated estimates?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was hoping for a pointer to a general survey addressing similar questions for the various types of multivariate interpolations in common use. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="34" LastEditorUserId="34" LastEditDate="2010-07-28T07:58:52.320" LastActivityDate="2010-08-03T21:50:09.007" Title="Multivariate Interpolation Approaches" Tags="&lt;multivariable&gt;&lt;interpolation&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="12" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="7" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:18:41.370" Score="21" Body="&lt;p&gt;See my response to &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2252144/datasets-for-running-statistical-analysis-on/2252450#2252450&quot;&gt;&quot;Datasets for Running Statistical Analysis on&quot;&lt;/a&gt; in reference to datasets in R.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="5" LastActivityDate="2010-07-19T19:18:41.370" CommentCount="1" CommunityOwnedDate="2011-08-12T20:29:33.010" />
  <row Id="13" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2010-07-19T19:18:56.800" Score="18" Body="&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning seems to have its basis in the pragmatic - a Practical observation or simulation of reality.  Even within statistics, mindless &quot;checking of models and assumptions&quot; can lead to discarding methods that are useful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, years ago, the very first commercially available (and working) Bankruptcy model implemented by the credit bureaus was created through a plain old linear regression model targeting a 0-1 outcome.  Technically, that's a bad approach, but practically, it worked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastActivityDate="2010-07-19T19:18:56.800" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="250872" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="99088" CreationDate="2016-12-11T02:50:48.533" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;As another user stated in the comments above, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wald%E2%80%93Wolfowitz_runs_test&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;runs test&lt;/a&gt; is the way to analyze your shooting data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would like to also point you towards &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/the-hot-hand-debate-gets-flipped-on-its-head-1443465711&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;this research&lt;/a&gt; since it's directly related to your analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="131198" LastActivityDate="2016-12-11T02:50:48.533" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="250873" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="250791" CreationDate="2016-12-11T03:17:13.647" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;Hazard ratios apply to many more situations than control/intervention groups. If you have a continuous predictor like age or blood pressure, the hazard ratio in a Cox regression would be the change in hazard per unit change in age or pressure. If you have a categorical predictor (say, multiple subtypes of a disease as in breast cancer, or gender) then you arbitrarily choose one category as a reference against which to compare the others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the control/intervention context it's certainly usual to choose the control as the reference group. I am, however, aware of no law requiring that. In some contexts you might choose to switch reference groups or the direction of a continuous variable (e.g., hazard per year decrease rather than per year increase in age). For example, when you examine a plot of the relative entries of predictors as the penalty changes in a LASSO model it's most convenient (at least for me) for the predictors to have either all HR &gt;1 or all &amp;lt;1, obtained with appropriate choices of reference levels or directions, so that all the curves start by pointing all up or all down when they leave the horizontal axis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are reading, pay careful attention to the authors' choice of reference level. If you are writing, choose reference levels that make it easiest to explain to your audience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="28500" LastActivityDate="2016-12-11T03:17:13.647" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="250874" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2016-12-11T03:39:10.853" Score="0" ViewCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;What is the equation for a multivariate skewed normal distribution, specifically a two dimensional skewed normal distribution?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="141935" LastActivityDate="2016-12-11T03:39:10.853" Title="Bivariate Skewed Normal Distribution" Tags="&lt;statistical-significance&gt;&lt;mathematical-statistics&gt;&lt;summary-statistics&gt;&lt;mathematics&gt;&lt;mathematica&gt;" AnswerCount="0" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="250875" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2016-12-11T04:06:00.993" Score="0" ViewCount="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have not studied statistics, and that's why I come here asking for help. While my question involves mentioning Python, it is not a necessity to know anything about Python for my question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I'm using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pythonhosted.org/libpgm/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; for Python which allows me to build Bayesian networks very easily. Currently I'm only building discrete networks, avoiding Gaussian distributions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This library allows me to define the edges and vertices of a Bayesian network, and it then calculates the prior probabilities from a set of data samples, then proceeds calculating the joint probability distribution for each random variable, using my defined graph.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I've only used 80% of the set of data samples, as I wanted to use the remaining 20% for a simple cross validation. I had hoped to compare the results of different models I built using this methodology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My question:&lt;/strong&gt; What's a &lt;em&gt;good enough&lt;/em&gt; way of testing my models?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My guesses:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brute force&lt;/em&gt;. I could calculate the exact probability of getting my test set (20%) using the joint probability distribution. However, this would lead to an &lt;strong&gt;extremely&lt;/strong&gt; small number, as the test set contains 400 samples, and I have &lt;strong&gt;8 random variables&lt;/strong&gt;. Doing this for my models, I could see which has the highest chance of getting the test set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gibbs sampling&lt;/em&gt;. I could use Gibbs or Monte Carlo sampling to try and get an estimate of the probability of getting the test set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another question: Should order matter in which I get the data samples? I.e. if sample=5 yields result &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt;, and test set contains &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; at position 6, would it still count as a &lt;em&gt;correct&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="141937" LastActivityDate="2016-12-11T04:06:00.993" Title="How is cross validation performed for Bayesian networks" Tags="&lt;bayesian&gt;&lt;cross-validation&gt;&lt;bayesian-network&gt;" AnswerCount="0" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="250876" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2016-12-11T04:12:08.133" Score="0" ViewCount="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;From the mtcars dataset, we can get the first word of the rownames by using:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a = strsplit(rownames(mtcars), &quot; &quot;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then by using sapply, we can get the first word of each element of a.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sapply(a, &quot;[[&quot;,1)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My question is how does that even work? How does &quot;[[&quot;,1 work as a function in sapply?&#xA;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plot.ly/r/pie-charts/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;I found this in a plotly example while looking for a way to make a donut chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="141582" LastActivityDate="2016-12-11T04:12:08.133" Title="How does &quot;[[&quot; work as a function in sapply?" Tags="&lt;r&gt;" AnswerCount="0" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="250877" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="249617" CreationDate="2016-12-11T04:14:54.610" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;Sounds like you're still stuck so I'll try and prompt you further. I'll use the following notation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$\begin{align}&#xA;X_{t}&amp;amp;=a+\phi X_{t-1}+Z_{t}\\&#xA;Z_{t}&amp;amp;\sim\text{WN}(0,\sigma^{2})&#xA;\end{align}$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You want to know:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$\begin{align}&#xA;\gamma=\text{Cov}(X_{t},X_{t-1})&amp;amp;=E[X_{t}X_{t-1}]-E[X_{t}]E[X_{t-1}]\\&#xA;\text{Cov}(X_{t},X_{t-1})&amp;amp;=E[X_{t}X_{t-1}]-E[X_{t}]^{2}\,\,\, \text{ (stationarity)}&#xA;\end{align}$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, we know:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$\begin{align}&#xA;X_{t}&amp;amp;=a+\phi X_{t-1}+Z_{t}\\&#xA;X_{t}X_{t-1}&amp;amp;=aX_{t-1}+\phi X_{t-1}^{2}+X_{t-1}Z_{t}\\&#xA;E[X_{t}X_{t-1}]&amp;amp;=aE[X_{t-1}]+\phi E[X_{t-1}^{2}]+E[X_{t-1}Z_{t}]\\&#xA;E[X_{t}X_{t-1}]&amp;amp;=aE[X_{t-1}]+\phi E[X_{t-1}^{2}]+0&#xA;\end{align}$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So we need the terms in the equation above. Let's start with $E[X_{t-1}]$:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$\begin{align}&#xA;X_{t-1}&amp;amp;=a+\phi X_{t-2}+Z_{t-1}\\&#xA;E[X_{t-1}]&amp;amp;=a+E[\phi X_{t-2}]+E[Z_{t-1}]\\&#xA;E[X_{t-1}]&amp;amp;=a+\phi E[X_{t-1}]+0\,\,\,\, \text{ (stationarity)}\\&#xA;E[X_{t-1}](1-\phi)&amp;amp;=a\\&#xA;E[X_{t-1}]&amp;amp;=\frac{a}{(1-\phi)}\\&#xA;\end{align}$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now we need $E[X_{t-1}^{2}]$:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$\begin{align}&#xA;X_{t-1}^{2}&amp;amp;=(a+\phi X_{t-2}+Z_{t-1})^{2}\\&#xA;X_{t-1}^{2}&amp;amp;=a^{2}+2a\phi X_{t-2}+2aZ_{t-1}+\phi^{2}X_{t-2}^{2}+2\phi X_{t-2}Z_{t-1}+Z_{t-1}^{2}\\&#xA;E[X_{t-1}^{2}]&amp;amp;=a^{2}+2a\phi E[X_{t-2}]+2aE[Z_{t-1}]+\phi^{2}E[X_{t-2}^{2}]+2\phi E[X_{t-2}Z_{t-1}]+E[Z_{t-1}^{2}]\\&#xA;E[X^{2}_{t-1}]&amp;amp;=a^{2}+2a\phi E[X_{t-1}]+0+\phi^{2}E[X^{2}_{t-1}]+0+E[Z^{2}_{t-1}]\,\,\,\, \text{ (stationarity)}\\&#xA;E[X^{2}_{t-1}](1-\phi^{2})&amp;amp;=a^{2}+\frac{2a^{2}\phi}{(1-\phi)}+\sigma^{2}\\&#xA;E[X^{2}_{t-1}]&amp;amp;=\frac{a^{2}}{(1-\phi^{2})}+\frac{2a^{2}\phi}{(1-\phi)(1-\phi^{2})}+\frac{\sigma^{2}}{(1-\phi^{2})}\\&#xA;\end{align}$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So finally:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$\begin{align}&#xA;\text{Cov}(X_{t},X_{t-1})=E[X_{t}X_{t-1}]-E[X_{t}]^{2}&amp;amp;=aE[X_{t-1}]+\phi E[X_{t-1}^{2}]-E[X_{t}]^{2}\\&#xA;&amp;amp;=\frac{a^{2}}{(1-\phi)}+\phi\bigg(\frac{a^{2}}{(1-\phi^{2})}+\frac{2a^{2}\phi}{(1-\phi)(1-\phi^{2})}+\frac{\sigma^{2}}{(1-\phi^{2})}\bigg)-\frac{a^{2}}{(1-\phi)^{2}}\\&#xA;&amp;amp;=\frac{a^{2}(1-\phi)(1+\phi)+a^{2}\phi(1-\phi)+2a^{2}\phi^{2}-a^{2}(1+\phi)}{(1-\phi)^{2}(1+\phi)}+\phi\frac{\sigma^{2}}{(1-\phi^{2})}\\&#xA;&amp;amp;=\frac{a^{2}-a^{2}\phi^{2}+2a^{2}\phi^{2}+a^{2}\phi-a^{2}\phi^{2}-a^{2}-a^{2}\phi}{(1-\phi)^{2}(1+\phi)}+\phi\frac{\sigma^{2}}{(1-\phi^{2})}\\&#xA;&amp;amp;=\phi\frac{\sigma^{2}}{(1-\phi^{2})}\\&#xA;\end{align}$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="102399" LastActivityDate="2016-12-11T04:14:54.610" CommentCount="0" />
</posts>